an application programming interface or api is a way for two computers to talk
应用程序编程接口或api 是两台计算机
to each other using an api is just like using a website in your browser but
使用 api 相互通信的一种方式，就像在浏览器中使用网站一样，但
instead of clicking buttons and filling out forms you write code to explicitly
不是单击按钮和填写表单，而是编写代码来明确地
request data from a server for example we could visit the nasa website to look
从服务器请求数据我们可以访问 nasa 网站来
at asteroids or we could use their rest api to request the raw json data that is
查看小行星，或者我们可以使用它们的 restapi 来请求屏幕上显示的原始 json 数据，
shown on the screen now most apis in the world are restful which means they
现在世界上大多数 api都是安静的，这意味着它们
follow a set of rules or constraints known as representational state transfer
遵循一组称为代表性的规则或约束
which has been the de facto standard for api development since the early 2000s a
自 2000 年代初以来，状态转移一直是
restful api organizes data entities or resources into a bunch of unique urls
api 开发的事实上的标准
well technically not urls but uris or uniform resource identifiers that
differentiate different types of data resources on a server a client can get
客户端可以
data about a resource by making a request to that endpoint over http the
通过 http 向该端点发出请求来获取有关资源的数据，
request message has a very specific format most importantly the start line
请求消息具有非常特定的格式 重要的是，起始行
contains the uri that you wish to access which is preceded by an http verb or
包含您希望访问的 uri，它前面是一个 http 动词或
request method which signal your intent with the resource a get request means
请求方法，它表明您对资源的意图 get 请求意味着
you just want to read the data while post means you want to create a new
您只想读取数据，而post 意味着您想要创建一个新
resource patch is for updates delete is for removing data along with a few other
资源 patch 用于更新 delete用于删除数据以及
methods beyond those below the start line we have headers which contain
除起始行之外的其他一些方法我们有包含
metadata about the request the accept header can tell the server you want the
有关请求的元数据的标头接受标头可以告诉服务器您想要
data in a specific format or the authorization header can be used to tell
特定格式的数据或授权标头可以 用于
the server that you're actually allowed to make that request then following the
告诉服务器您实际上被允许发出该请求，然后在
headers we have the body which contains a custom payload of data the server will
标头之后我们有包含自定义数据有效负载的正文，服务器将
receive the request message then execute some code usually to read from a
接收请求消息然后执行一些代码通常从
database that can then be formatted into a response message the top of the
数据库中读取 然后被格式化为响应消息，消息的顶部
message contains a status code to tell the client what happened to their
包含一个状态代码，告诉客户端他们的
request codes at the 200 level mean that things went well at the 400 level it
请求代码在 200 级别发生了什么 表示事情在 400 级别进展顺利，这
means something was wrong with your request and at the 500 level it means
意味着您的请求有问题，在 500 级别，这
that the server failed after the status code we then have the response headers
意味着服务器在状态代码后失败，然后我们有响应标头
which contain information about the server that's followed by the response
，其中包含有关服务器的信息，然后是响应
body which contains the data payload and is usually formatted in json when
正文 它包含数据有效负载，并且在谈论 apis 时通常以 json 格式
talking about apis now an important part of this architecture is that it's
现在该架构的一个重要部分是它是
stateless which means that the two parties don't need to store any
无状态的，这意味着双方不需要存储任何
information about each other and every request response cycle is independent
关于彼此的信息，并且每个请求响应周期都是独立的
from all other communication and this leads to well-behaved web applications
从所有其他通信中，这导致行为良好的 Web 应用
that are predictable and reliable this has been restful apis in 100 seconds if
程序是可预测和可靠的，如果您喜欢它，这已经是 100 秒内宁静的 API，
you enjoyed it leave a comment below then next week i'll pick out the best
请在下面留下评论，然后下周我会挑选出最好
one to win this free t-shirt and now it's time to go beyond 100 seconds to
的来赢得这个免费 t  -shirt现在是时候超越 100 秒
build a restful api from scratch the most popular framework for building
从头开始构建一个 RESTful api最流行的
restful apis in node is express.js it's been around forever and it's very
在 node 中构建 RESTful api 的框架是 e  xpress.js 它一直存在，
minimal and easy to learn if you know a little bit of javascript over the next
如果您在接下来的几分钟内了解一点 javascript，它非常简单且易于学习，
few minutes we'll use express to build our own restful api from scratch you'll
我们将使用 express从头开始构建我们自己的 restful api 您将学习
learn how to create different endpoints for your api we'll also look at slightly
如何创建不同的端点对于您的 api，我们还将研究
more advanced concepts like middleware and tools in the cloud for deploying
更高级的概念，例如云中的中间件和工具，用于部署
your api like api gateways to get started you'll want to open up vs code
您的 api，例如 api gateways 以开始您需要将 vs 代码打开
to an empty directory you'll need to have node.js installed and i'm using
到您需要拥有节点的空目录.js 已安装并且我在
version 12 for this video to start a new node project let's run npm init y from
此视频中使用版本 12 来启动一个新的节点项目让我们从命令行运行 npm init y
the command line this will create a package json and give
这将创建一个包 json 并为
us a context for installing packages that we can use in node like express
我们提供安装包的上下文，我们可以在 node 中使用这些包，例如 express
let's go ahead and install express using npm install you'll notice that adds
让我们继续使用 npm install 安装 express你会注意到在 package.json 文件中添加
express to our dependencies in the package.json file from there we'll need
express 到我们的依赖项中，我们需要
a file to write our code in so let's create an index.js file at the top of
一个文件来编写我们的代码，所以让我们在顶部创建一个 index.js 文件
that file we'll declare a variable for app which represents the actual api that
我们将声明的那个文件 app 的一个变量，它代表
we're building and its value is an import of the express package which
我们正在构建的实际 api，它的值是 express 包的导入，它
itself is a function so we'll add parentheses after it to initialize it
本身就是一个函数，所以我们将在它之后添加括号来初始化
now at this point our api hasn't defined any endpoints but let's go ahead and run
它，此时我们的 api 还没有定义任何端点，但让我们继续运行
it anyway the way you fire up your api on the server is by calling app.listen
它，您在服务器上启动 api 的方式是通过调用 app.listen
that tells it to listen on a specific port which we've defined as its own
告诉它侦听我们定义为它自己的
separate variable as 8080. then as an optional second argument to listen we
单独变量为 8080 的特定端口。然后作为 一个可选的第二个监听参数，我们
can fire a callback to let us know when the api is ready and we'll just have it
可以触发一个回调，让我们知道api 何时准备好，我们只需让它
console log the main url we can now run the api by going to the terminal and
控制台记录主 url，我们现在可以通过转到终端和
running node period to run that index.js file and it should console.log it's live
运行节点期间运行 api 来运行它 index.js文件，它应该
on localhost 8080. if we paste the url into the browser you can see we get a
在 localhost 8080 上运行 console.log。如果我们将 url 粘贴到浏览器中，您会看到我们收到
message of cannot get that's because we don't have any api endpoints set up yet
无法获取的消息，因为我们还没有设置任何 api 端点，
but express is still responding with an error message in fact you can open up
但 express 是 仍然以错误消息响应实际上您可以
the network tab in chrome if we look closely we can see that our server
如果我们仔细观察，在 chrome 中打开网络选项卡，我们可以看到我们的服务器
responded with a 404 status code meaning that page was not found at this point we
以 404 状态代码响应，这意味着此时未找到该页面我们
know our api is working but debugging it in the browser is usually not the best
知道我们的 api 正在工作，但在浏览器中调试它通常不是最佳
option there are many different ways we can access our api we could use curl
选择 有许多不同的方式可以访问我们的 api 我们可以从命令行使用 curl
from the command line we could install a vs code extension or we could use a rest
我们可以安装一个vs 代码扩展或者我们可以使用
client like insomnia or postman i'm going to be using insomnia throughout
像 insomnia 或 postman 这样的休息客户端 我将在
the rest of this video because it provides a really nice way to format
本视频的其余部分使用 insomnia 因为它提供了一种非常好的方式来格式化
your requests and also view a history of all your interactions from insomnia we
您的请求并查看您与失眠症的所有交互历史我们
can create a new request then simply paste in our url
可以创建一个新请求然后简单地粘贴到我们的 url
we can easily change the http verb from the drop down menu here click send and
我们可以从这里的下拉菜单中轻松更改 http 动词单击发送和
then get the response in a nicely formatted developer friendly way we can
然后以格式良好的开发人员友好方式获取响应，我们
even see the timeline here with our request in yellow and the response in
甚至可以在这里看到时间线，我们的请求为黄色，响应为
green but now we need to get back to our javascript and add an endpoint to the
绿色，但现在我们需要回到我们的javascript 并添加一个 endp 对于
api we can do that by changing an http verb to the app instance if you type a
api，我们可以通过将 http动词更改为应用程序实例来做到这一点，如果您
period after app you'll get intellisense on a bunch of different methods that
在应用程序之后键入一个句点，您将在该对象上的一堆不同方法上获得智能感知
live on this object and you'll notice methods for git post patch etc which
，您会注意到git post patch 的方法 etc
represent different http verbs if we want to add a get endpoint to the
代表不同的http动词如果我们想向t-shirt uri添加一个get端点，
t-shirt uri we can do that by passing t-shirt as its first argument
我们可以通过传递t-shirt作为它的第一个参数
that'll automatically set up our server with that endpoint then it's our job to
来做到这一点，它将自动使用该端点设置我们的服务器，然后我们的工作就是
handle a request to it which we do by passing a callback function as the
处理 每当客户端或最终用户请求该 url 时，我们通过将回调函数作为
second argument whenever a client or end user requests that url it will fire this
第二个参数传递给它的请求，它将触发此
callback function to handle the request the function itself provides access to
回调函数来处理请求，函数本身提供对
two different objects the request object and the response object the request is
两个不同对象的访问，请求对象和响应 object 请求
the incoming data while the response is the data we want to send back to the
是传入的数据，而响应是我们要发送回客户端的数据，
client the most important thing it does is allow us to send a response back to
它所做的最重要的事情是允许我们向客户端发送响应，
the client that response can have a status code like 200 for an ok response
该响应可以具有状态 类似 200 的代码表示 ok 响应，
then we can send a data payload along with it if we pass a javascript object
然后我们可以发送一个数据有效负载，如果我们传递一个 javascript 对象
as the argument then it will send that data back as json by default let's go
作为参数，那么默认情况下它将将该数据作为 json 发送回让我们
ahead and save the file then restart the server from the terminal from insomnia
继续保存文件，然后从 从 insomnia 终端
we can then make a get request to localhost 8080 t-shirt when we do that
我们可以向localhost 8080 t-shirt 发出一个获取请求，当我们这样做时，
we get a json object back as the response body with a status code of 200.
我们会返回一个 json 对象作为响应体，状态码为 200。
that's pretty cool but now let's go back to our code and add a second endpoint
这很酷，但现在让我们回到我们的代码并添加 这次是第二个端点，
this time a post endpoint followed by a slash and a dynamic url parameter that
后跟一个斜线和一个动态 url 参数，
represents the id of that t-shirt there might be millions of different t-shirts
表示该 T 恤的 id，这个 API 上可能有数百万种不同的 T 恤
on this api and a dynamic url allows us to handle all of them from a single
，动态 url 允许我们处理所有这些
function when dealing with a post request it means that the user is trying
处理 post请求时的单个函数意味着用户正在尝试
to create new data on the server or create a new t-shirt in this case first
在服务器上创建新数据或创建新 T 恤在这种情况下首先
we need the id which we can get from the url and its value is made available to
我们需要我们可以从 url 获取的 id并生成它的值 可根据要求提供给
us on the request parameters object second we also need a logo for the
我们 st 参数对象第二个我们还需要
t-shirt but the logo is contained in the request body which if you remember from
T 恤的徽标，但徽标包含在请求正文中，如果您之前记得，它
earlier is a custom data payload contained in the incoming request in
是传入请求中包含的自定义数据有效负载，
other words the request object in express allows us to access information
换句话说，快递中的请求对象允许我们
from the request message like the url parameters the body the headers etc and
从请求消息中访问信息，例如 url参数、正文、标题等
now that we have that information we could use it to save a new record to the
database or something along those lines that's beyond the scope of this video
what we'll do for right now is check to make sure that we have a logo in the
现在要做的是检查以确保我们在
request body and if we don't then we'll send an error response with a 418 status
请求正文中有一个徽标，如果我们没有，那么我们将发送一个带有 418 状态代码的错误响应
code and an error message that we need a logo
和一条错误消息，我们需要一个徽标，
but assuming we do have a valid logo we can just send a response with a t-shirt
但假设我们有 有一个有效的标志，我们可以发送一个
that contains that logo and id now let's go back to insomnia and we'll make a
包含该标志和 id 的 T 恤的响应现在让我们回到 insomnia，我们
post request to that t-shirt endpoint followed by a unique id that can be
将向该 T 恤端点发出一个发布请求，然后是一个唯一的 id，可以是
whatever you want then in the body section we'll go ahead and add a request
任何东西 那么你想要 在正文部分，我们将继续添加
body with a format of json and it's just a json object that contains a logo with
格式为 json 的请求正文，它只是一个包含带有字符串值的徽标的 json 对象，
a string value if we send that request you'll notice we get a 500 error
如果我们发送该请求，您会注意到我们收到 500 错误
response which means our api code is broken so what's going on here it's
响应，这意味着 我们的 api 代码被破坏了，所以这里发生了什么它
telling us we have a runtime error because we can't destructure the
告诉我们我们有一个运行时错误，因为我们无法
property logo from the request body the reason for that is that express does not
从请求正文中解构属性 logo原因是 express 不会
parse json in the body by default not everybody uses express to build a json
默认解析正文中的 json 不是每个人都使用 express 构建一个 json
api so that's not the default behavior what we need to do here is set up
api，所以这不是默认行为我们需要在这里做的是设置
middleware that tells express to parse json before the actual data hits the
中间件，告诉express 在实际数据到达
function that we're using here to handle the request when you hear the term
我们在这里用来处理请求的函数之前解析 json当你听到这个术语时
middleware think of shared code that runs before every endpoint callback that
中间件考虑在您定义的每个端点回调之前运行的共享代码，
you've defined very common middleware is built into express itself we can
非常常见的中间件内置于 express 本身中，我们可以
refactor our code here a little bit to make a variable for express and then we
在这里稍微重构我们的代码，为 express 创建一个变量，然后我们
can call app.use to apply middleware in this case the middleware we want to
可以调用 app. 在这种情况下用于应用中间件，我们要
apply is the express.json middleware now every request that comes in will first
应用的中间件是 express.json 中间件，现在每个进来的请求都将
go through this express json middleware which will convert the body to json
首先通过这个 express json 中间件，该中间件会将 body 转换为 json，
therefore making it available in our post callback let's go ahead and save
因此在我们的post 回调中可用，让我们开始吧 提前保存，
restart our server and then go back to insomnia and if we send the same exact
重新启动我们的服务器，然后返回insomnia，如果我们发送相同的确切
request you'll notice this time we get back a successful response
请求，您会注意到这次我们会收到成功的响应
in addition if we make the logo an empty string and try to send the same request
，此外，如果我们将徽标设为空字符串并尝试发送相同的请求，
we get a 418 response along with a message that we need a logo
我们 收到 418 响应以及一条消息，我们需要一个徽标
congratulations you just built a restful api from scratch with node.js and
恭喜您刚刚使用 node.js 和 express 从头构建了一个 restful api，
express but before we wrap up the video there's one more thing you should
但是在我们结束视频之前，您还应该知道一件事
definitely know about when it comes to restful apis and that is the open api
关于restful api 这就是开放的 api
spec which provides a standard way to describe an api in yaml it originally
规范，它提供了一种在 yaml 中描述 api 的标准方法，它最初
came about in something called the swagger framework and what it allows you
是在称为swagger 框架的东西中出现的，它允许
to do is describe your api in a way that can be understood by both humans and
你做的是描述以人类和机器都可以理解的方式创建您的 api
machines and if you're building a serious api you get all kinds of awesome
，如果您正在构建一个严肃的 api，您将
benefits in the process your api will be fully documented making it much easier
在此过程中获得各种令人敬畏的好处，您的 api 将被完整记录，从而
for the end user to work with and because it follows a standard format you
使最终用户更容易工作 并且因为它遵循标准格式，您
can actually just automatically generate all of your client-side or server-side
实际上可以自动生成所有客户端或服务器端
code what i'm using right now is a free tool called swaggerhub and i can come up
代码我现在使用的是一个名为 swaggerhub 的免费工具，我可以来到
here and hit the export button to automatically generate a bunch of
这里并点击导出按钮自动生成一堆
boilerplate code now i'm usually not a huge fan of code generators but there's
样板代码现在我通常不是代码生成器的忠实拥护者，但是当您
a more powerful reason to use open api when you describe your api with the open
使用开放 api 规范描述您的 api 时，使用开放 api 有更强有力的理由，
api spec you can then upload the configuration to tools like api gateway
然后您可以将配置上传到 api gateway 等工具
on aws or google cloud where it can be secured monitored and connected to
在 aws 或谷歌云上，可以对其进行安全监控并连接到
backend infrastructure let me know if you want to see a full tutorial on that
后端基础架构，如果您想查看有关该主题的完整教程，请告诉我，
topic but i'm going to go ahead and wrap things up there and if you want access
但我将继续在那里完成所有内容，如果您 想要
to even more advanced content consider becoming a pro member at fireship io
访问更高级的内容考虑成为 fireship io 的专业会员
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢收看，我们下期再见